Akhil G Krishnan

akhil@saeloun.com <u>Github</u>, <u>LinkedIn</u>

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I'm a software developer at Saeloun Inc, with over 2 years of experience in web development. I've experience with Ruby on Rails, ReactJS. Over the course of my career, I've led a five member team to build an application from scratch. I contribute to Open Source and have contributed to Ruby on Rails.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Key Skills: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Python, JavaScript, GoLang, Django, C, ReactJS, Tailwind CSS

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools: Heroku, Postman, Test::Unit, RSpec, REST APIs, Kafka, Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

Saeloun Inc (September 2021 – present)

Software Developer

- Wanderwhale

Ruby on Rails, React

- Worked on configuration and deployment setup for the app.
- Worked on fixing production level bugs.

- Miru

Ruby on Rails, React, TypeScript, Tailwind, PostgreSQL

Miru is a time tracking and invoicing tool for small and medium sized businesses.

- Designed the database and the system architecture.
- Developed and maintained the entire web application.
- Managed team to build robust and scalable application.
- Worked on adding new features and fixing the bugs.
- Handled all the deployment process.
- **ActivateCare** (Via Saeloun Inc)

Ruby on Rails, React, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap

ActivateCare is a cloud-based CareHubTM that connects patients, families, care teams, and community services on the journey to health and well-being.

- Worked on adding new features and bug fixes.
- Worked on redesigning the patient summary.
- Worked on SDOH Referral tracking system.
- Tasked with implementing the custom reusable design components.
- Worked with transition of application from a hospital driven solution to community driven health solution.

Sapaad Software Pvt Lmt (August 2020 – July 2021)

<u>Junior Software Developer</u>

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, ReactJS, PostgreSQL, Golang

Sapaad is a SaaS company having a cloud based restaurant management point of sale system.

- Sapaad POS

Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Bootstrap, Kafka

- Worked on integrating GPay Food aggregator to the core application.
- Worked on multilingual translation.
- Developed a two level caching mechanism for fetching the menu items in a faster manner.
- Built Kafka mechanism for message broadcasting to all external dependent services.

- Sapaad Direct

Ruby on Rails, ReactJS

Sapaad Direct is a BYOD platform for walk-in orders. Customers can directly make an order with their own device by simply scanning a QR code.

- Worked on integrating PayTabs and PayU payment services.
- Built the API backend using Ruby on Rails from scratch.
- Worked on developing the frontend using ReactJS.

- Sapaad DMMS

Ruby on Rails, ReactJS, Redis, Kafka, Docker

Sapaad DMMS is a delivery manager application, for handling all delivery orders of a restaurant.

- Worked on both frontend and backend services.
- Built Kafka mechanism for data handling.

- Sapaad Trial Manager

Ruby on Rails, jQuery, PostgreSQL, Kafka, Docker

Sapaad Trail Manager is a trial application management system for the Sapaad sales team to track each customer trial application.

- Worked as lead on this project.
- Developed robust, scalable, and maintainable Rails applications, with high test coverage.
- Created the design and architecture.
- Managed overall project and delivered in three months.

EDUCATION

Providence College of Engineering, Chengannur, Kerala (2016 – 2020)

Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science & Engineering)